# Michael Palmer

palmer.mikepalmer@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/get-palmer • (980) 333-3936 • Houston, TX

#### **SUMMARY**

Front-end-focused software engineer with a strong background in data visualisation and enterprise applications, particularly in the oil and gas sector. Expert in React, modern JavaScript, and creating performant, reusable UI components. Combines design sensibility with the ability to integrate complex data sources into intuitive user interfaces. Experienced collaborating across engineering, data science, and business teams to deliver impactful tools.

#### **EDUCATION**

| Hack Reactor   Full Stack Software Engineering Immersive           | 2021 |
|--|------|
| University of Oklahoma   Bachelor of Science Petroleum Engineering | 2014 |

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Front-End | JavaScript (ES6), React, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, DOM manipulation
Back-End | REST API, RabbitMQ, Python, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, FastAPI
Testing/Deployment | Test driven development, Object oriented design, Heroku, Vercel, Docker
Development | Git, Dev tools, VS Code, Insomnia/Postman, Agile workflow, 3rd Party APIs
Recent | Prototyping AI-enhanced workflows/learning

# **SOFTWARE ENGINEERING APPLICATIONS**

Fullstack Engineer & UI Design Manager - 2021 | github.com/hratx-blue-ocean/otter-people

Project 'Otter People' Networking & Events | React w/ hooks, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, AWS EC2

- Generates travel and activity recommendations with accommodation suggestions for group events
- Easily schedule group events using app's suggested activities widget based on the geolocation of 'otters' in group
- Deployed full app on heroku and also hosted back-end w/ MongoDB on AWS EC2 instance

# Front-End Engineer - 2021 | github.com/Mike-Ikes/Products

Project Clothing Store Questions and Answers | React, Node.js, Express, Material-UI, AWS EC2

- Built questions and answers (Q&A) feature frontend from scratch and merged with main frontend codebase
- Responsible for building primary components of Q&A including questions and answers lists, ask a question modal/form, report question or answer, add answer modal/form, elastic search bar with dynamic Q&As filtering
- Utilized React hooks with forms to create intuitive user experiences with custom validation methods

# **Back-end Software Engineer - 2021**

Project Product Overview API and Database | React, Node.js, MongoDB, Express, AWS EC2, Artillery, Jest

- Built API and generated 10M+ records of data in MongoDB database for performance testing
- Tested API and database with loader.io and optimized to give over 2575 rps performance

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Frontend React Developer | EOG Resources – Remote 2022

- Created multiple data-visualization solutions for several enterprise level react-applications
- Created reusable services (UI + API) with backend team to be used in react apps org-wide

# **Full Stack Engineer** | Galvanize Inc. / Hack Reactor – *Remote*

2020-2022

- Created multiple data-visualization solutions for several enterprise level react-applications
- Created reusable services (UI + API) with backend team to be used in react apps org-wide

# **Applications Engineer** | Baker Hughes – *Midland, TX*

2018-2020

- Managed performance analysis and optimizations of oilfield drill bit designs
- Created interactive data-driven dashboards within Tableau, Power BI, and TIBCO Spotfire through an ETL approach utilizing SQL, R-script, Python, and Power Query (M-Lang) methods

**Technical Engineer** | Baker Hughes – Global (United Arab Emirates, Saudi Arabia, Oman, Argentina, USA) 2014-2018

- Performed engineering studies and bids, leading to winning \$300M project in Saudi Aramco's Shaybah field
- Analyzed key performance indicators to determine which project areas were leading to suboptimal performance